But, even though we are aware of the problems, a lot is getting worse.
We have to work a lot more for our sea.
More and more people use the sea.
We need the sea for food.
There are more and more recreation boats for recreation.
Fishing.
Everything, everything needs much more space.
We have to get a balance so that we in a sustainable way use the sea and not destroy it more than what we have done.
About the middle of the week, two of the environmental owners Bosse visited a Hönöbo with a heart for seal safaris in Gothenburg's northern archipelago.
Now we will take you out on a guided tour.
It is Harald, my granddaughter, and it is the third season he runs so he is experienced on this.
I am completely calm and can consider myself telling where we are somewhere.
In 2008 we were about 30 players.
This year we are over 100 players.
We have expanded with Halland, Skåne and Denmark.
We are more and more who want to join and that is proof that the issues are becoming more and more important.
I am passionate about the sea and feel that we have a long way to hike and we have to change our own behavior.
I see our over -consumption that leaves traces both here but also in Africa and other poorer countries
Which happens very badly because we consume too much in the Western world.
It's something that drives me pretty much.
Then of course I want a beautiful sea that I can enjoy, swim in,
Snorkel and discover that there is this huge life under the sea.
Then I get to learn something new every year and that is what is so fun about working in such a project.
Because I also learn all the time and the curiosity you have and develops never end.
I think that is wonderful.
The island of Måseskär is located at the far end of the sea band outside Orust.
The trip goes via Kärringön where we change a boat.
I have a chat with Tomas Liebig, a dedicated biologist who is happy to share his knowledge.
Actually, we should call the island of TrueSkär because here is more trout than seagulls.
The trotting we have in the largest number is herring.
This year, 200 pairs of herring are hedged here.
It has been good for them.
There are a lot of kids that may be heard in the background, the small ones feed by their parents.
There is a lot going on on Måseskär under the flag of the North Sea week.
And here you use rainwater.
Guidance on life as a lighthouse keeper, a lecture on the mythical storm vault,
But we listen to Tomas.
What is very special about Måseskär is that outside the island there are two sea currents that shock on each other.
It gets a stir in the water.
It is released a lot of nutrition.
We get plenty of plant and zooplankton.
Plenty of small fish thus tobis, small herring and then larger fish.
During the 30 years that Tomas regularly certainly on the island, he has seen how bird life has become different.
We hope that politicians will understand.
We simply want attention.
And we should have fun and support each other so there is not so much anxiety and lonely.
The sea is required to save the climate and the climate must be saved to save the sea.
So it's all about stopping eutrophication, sustainable food from the sea, quitting with large -scale fishing.
In the North Sea also lives a small algae called meat leaf.
It is red and it tastes fried egg.
The meat leaf hall requires us to protect the sea.
Our second requirement is about sustainable food from the sea.
First, fish sustainable.
We need to get rid of bottom line and other destructive methods that are actually subsidized today.